<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ubuntu on SwillOps</title>
    <link>http://swillops.com/tags/ubuntu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ubuntu on SwillOps</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://swillops.com/tags/ubuntu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Ubuntu in Parallel to Mac OSX</title>
      <link>http://swillops.com/blog/install-ubuntu-parallel-mac-osx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://swillops.com/blog/install-ubuntu-parallel-mac-osx/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;If you are trying to do this you will need &lt;a href=&#34;http://kb.parallels.com/entry/32/568/&#34;&gt;Parallels Desktop 3.0 for Mac
(~$79.99 USD)&lt;/a&gt;. This software allows
you to run Windows and Linux on your Mac so you have access to all three
operating systems without rebooting. I think this will be an ideal web
developing environment, but that is another article all together&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Install Parallels Desktop 3.0 for Mac and then launch it. Go to &lt;strong&gt;File -&amp;gt;
New&lt;/strong&gt;. In the new window select &lt;strong&gt;Typical&lt;/strong&gt;, then click &lt;strong&gt;(Next)&lt;/strong&gt;. Select
&lt;strong&gt;Linux&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Ubuntu Linux&lt;/strong&gt;, then click &lt;strong&gt;(Next)&lt;/strong&gt;. Finish the guide with
the appropriate information that you want for the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got an error when I tried to install Ubuntu 7.10 (Gutsy):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The display server has been shut down about 6 times in the last 90 seconds.
It is likely that something bad is going on. Waiting for 2 minutes before
trying again on display.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you get this error, follow &lt;a href=&#34;http://kb.parallels.com/entry/32/568/&#34;&gt;this
guide&lt;/a&gt; in the very good knowledge base
provided by Parallels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;troubleshooting-section:ed60267dc24e98ddc27c68ab970f1367&#34;&gt;Troubleshooting Section:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;you-can-t-update-ubuntu:ed60267dc24e98ddc27c68ab970f1367&#34;&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t Update Ubuntu&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have to manually connect to your internet connection. Just go up to the
top right of your Ubuntu screen and select &amp;lsquo;Wired Network&amp;rsquo; from the network
monitor and it will connect (assuming your Mac has an internet connection).
Also since the install could not find a connection, it may have commented out
all of your repositories in &lt;code&gt;/etc/apt/sources.list&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;http://
ubuntuguide.org/wiki/Ubuntu:Gutsy#Manual_Method_for_Adding_Repositories&#34;&gt;Follow this guide&lt;/a&gt; to
set up your repositories (you should probably use these repositories anyway).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;can-t-start-ubuntu-after-an-update:ed60267dc24e98ddc27c68ab970f1367&#34;&gt;Can&amp;rsquo;t start Ubuntu after an Update&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some reason &lt;strong&gt;single&lt;/strong&gt; gets added back into the string &lt;code&gt;kernel /boot/....&lt;/code&gt;
in your &lt;code&gt;/boot/grub/menu.lst&lt;/code&gt; file. Refer back to &lt;a href=&#34;http://kb.parallels.com/entry/32/568/&#34;&gt;step 5 in this
guide&lt;/a&gt; to fix that problem.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; My machine crashed after the update and before the reboot which may
have caused this issue.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;cant-use-full-screen-resolution:ed60267dc24e98ddc27c68ab970f1367&#34;&gt;Cant use Full Screen Resolution&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are getting warnings telling you that you cant set a resolution that
size when you start the Ubuntu machine, &lt;a href=&#34;http://muffinresearch.co.uk/archives/2006/08/13/running-ubuntu-under-
parallels-desktop-for-mac/&#34;&gt;check out this
article&lt;/a&gt;. Basically, changing the setting in
&lt;code&gt;/etc/X11/xorg.conf&lt;/code&gt; does not work, you have to use &lt;code&gt;sudo dpkg-reconfigure 
-phigh xserver-xorg&lt;/code&gt; to change the resolution settings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point you should be set. Enjoy the wonderfulness of Linux on your
Mac&amp;hellip; :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu: An Alternative to Windows</title>
      <link>http://swillops.com/blog/ubuntu-alternative-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://swillops.com/blog/ubuntu-alternative-windows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I think Windows release of Vista is a turning point in the desktop environment
landscape. People are going to start looking for alternatives instead of
trying to relearn how to use their computer, all the while dealing with the
fact that it is slower than it ever was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Windows has been on this train for a while now. Their entire business model
has pretty much been; build a product, ship it, support it for a little while,
ship a new product and force the user to upgrade. That is why you went from
95, to 98 (to realize it was 95 with bugz), Millennium (if you were really
unlucky), 2000, and then XP. And now you are considering &amp;lsquo;upgrading&amp;rsquo; to Vista.
So what have all these upgrades been giving you? Features&amp;hellip; Ya, thats pretty
much it. You are getting an extra 101 things that you will never use. Since
the interface can only support a set number of features, they have been trying
to cut down on space by replacing text with images. These images are getting
more and more ambiguous. For example, my uncle is an average computer user
whose new laptop came with Windows Vista installed. He worked his way around
it for a little while learning where everything was that had changed since XP.
When he went to shutdown his computer he was confused. He couldn&amp;rsquo;t find
shutdown. He called tech support to figure it out (and the person at the front
desk couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure it out either, so she had to transfer him to an actual
technician). Is this realistic? I don&amp;rsquo;t think so&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its not just the interface either. Windows has been developing most of its
software with &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moore%27s_Law&#34;&gt;Moores Law&lt;/a&gt; in
mind. This is basically the idea that every 18 months computers will have a
substantial improvement in resources. Because of this, they have been building
systems that are more and more resource dependent. When the Windows OS
(Operating System) loads, it takes a large chunk of your resources and never
frees them. All of your actual processing is done with the remaining
resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t believe that this was the best solution available, so about 2 years
ago I started looking for other options. This is when I came upon Ubuntu. Its
a Linux distribution that has been written with the user in mind. When I
started using it 2 years ago the project was relatively new and had some minor
annoyances. Now it is a completely different story. From the 10 minute
install, to the improved speed and functionality, I could never go back to
Windows. They have really thought out what the priorities should be for an OS
and have implemented the requirement beautifully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ubuntu and all the software you will use on it is free (for the most part,
unless you run Windows software on it). There is a repository system that you
get all of the software from as well as Ubuntu it self. Once installed, Ubuntu
and all installed software will be kept up to date with the most recent
releases through an online package management interface similar to Windows
Update. The major difference between Windows Update the the Ubuntu approach is
that EVERYTHING in Ubuntu is updated through this package manager. So if you
need to change drivers, install new software or just keep your system up to
date, everything is done through the same interface. This is beautiful because
all of the dependencies are taken care of behind the scenes so you just have
to tell it what you want and it will take care of everything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that some people will not be able to part with some of there Windows
software, but you don&amp;rsquo;t have to. You can actually run Windows software on
Linux through a program called &lt;a href=&#34;http://ubuntuguide.org/wiki/Ubuntu:Feist
y#How_to_install_and_run_Wine_.28Open_Source_version_of_CrossOver_Linux.29&#34;&gt;Wine&lt;/a&gt;. A
good example of how much better Ubuntu is than Windows is my experience with
World of Warcraft. I wanted to try the game, but my Windows machine couldn&amp;rsquo;t
run it because the system did not meet requirements. I figured I would give it
a shot in Ubuntu to see if I would have any luck. I installed it without too
much difficulty and after tweaking some graphics settings I was playing WoW on
my Linux machine (the exact same system that could not run it using Windows).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could go on and on with a list of reasons why you should switch, but I will
just get tired and you will get bored, so I will just give you a few links to
consider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ubuntu.com/&#34;&gt;Ubuntu Homepage&lt;/a&gt;: This is the Ubuntu homepage where
you can download the Live CD from. Once you burn the Live CD you will be able
to load Ubuntu without installing anything, so you can try the OS without
changing anything on your current system. Once you decide to install Ubuntu
you can just double click on the &amp;ldquo;Install&amp;rdquo; icon on the desktop and it will
walk you through the install. 10 minutes later you will be a Linux user
(probably with Windows on another partition)&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ubuntuforums.org/&#34;&gt;Ubuntu Forums&lt;/a&gt;: These are the Forums for Ubuntu.
There is a great community of people who can help you with any questions you
have. This is a great resource that doesn&amp;rsquo;t even exist for Windows users&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ubuntuguide.org/wiki/Ubuntu:Feisty&#34;&gt;Ubuntu Starter Guide&lt;/a&gt;: This is an
incredible resource for solving just about any problem with Ubuntu. Once you
install Ubuntu I would recommend checking out this page. This is probably the
best guide for anything you could ever want to do with the OS&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Computing&amp;hellip; :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu: backed by a great community</title>
      <link>http://swillops.com/blog/ubuntu-backed-great-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://swillops.com/blog/ubuntu-backed-great-community/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I promised to come back and visit the community aspect of Ubuntu because I
feel that it is an underrated feature of this OS. I&amp;rsquo;m sure most of you have
had an experience where you are trying to do something with Windows and you
just cant seem to figure it out. I have been in that situation many times and
I have always been kind of discouraged with the amount of support that I can
get. Its not that the answers are not out there, because for the most part
they are, but you can only really rely on google to find them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I switched to Ubuntu I had a reasonable foundation in Linux, but I was
still pretty green. There were a lot of basic things that I had to go looking
for because I didn&amp;rsquo;t understand how everything worked with this OS. I was
pleasantly surprised with the wealth of information and the willingness of
other people to help when I was searching for answers. Because Linux is open
source (for the most part), there is a huge community of people who know it
very well, and since a lot of the same questions get asked, many of them
already have guides written to solve most of your problems. Ubuntu has
centralized its community a bit by offering forums, wikis and technical
support. I cant remember a question that I have not been able to find the
answer to, either on the forums or with a quick google search.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>