<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Framework on SwillOps</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/framework/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Framework on SwillOps</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/framework/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Build it or just put it together???</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/build-it-or-just-put-it-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/build-it-or-just-put-it-together/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If your company is looking to update your online feature set, but don&amp;rsquo;t have
the technical expertise to do it your self, there are a lot of new options
that are tailored just for you. The price tag associated with getting a
professional looking and feature complete website online has always been a
major deterrent. If your company does not have a technical department up for
the challenge, it can be difficult to put together a manageable solution that
suits your needs and does not cost a fortune.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been a couple things of late that are changing this situation a
bit. Content management systems (CMS) such as Drupal are becoming very viable
solutions without a lot of technical overhead or financial investment. Another
major player in this context is the relatively new Ruby on Rails framework
which has been making waves due to its reduced development commitment, which
in turn can reduce the cost of a very finely tuned solution. Both of these
options can easily be considered if you are in the process of researching how
to upgrade your online presence. In this article I am going to quickly discuss
some of the pros and cons that come with both of these options, but it is also
important to point out that these two are not your only options and you should
still do a lot of research when making a big decision like this. Drupal is
currently my favorite CMS system, but to name a few more there is Joomla,
SimpleCMS, Typo3 and Expression Engine. Also, for fast and effective
development, Ruby on Rails is not without competition either. CodeIgniter is a
PHP development environment that has some very similar blood in its veins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what solution is right for you? If I could just write an article that
answered that for everyone I would be a very rich man. Unfortunately I am not
an oracle, so this answer has to be sought after through research and sound
technical advice. The long and the short of it really comes down to your
business. How do you operate? What is your budget? How often does your site
change? Who adds or updates content?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ruby on Rails (RoR) is a framework build on the powerful dynamic language of
Ruby. It caters to a small code base that complies very well with many best
practices in the industry. It is very good for fast agile development due to
its great separation of code along with many built in generators. RoR has also
integrated an Object-Relational Mapping (ORM) which completely removes SQL
queries from the code. What this does is create a mapping between the objects
and the relational database. This removes a lot of your database worries
because it means you can just write information to your objects and the
framework will automagically build and maintain the associated database. This
also makes implementing, moving, migrating or scaling your applications very
easy. RoR also has a built in test environment and automatically generates an
API for your application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since this is not meant to be a technical review, it suffices to say that Ruby
on Rails is a great development environment and can reduce development time by
30 to 50 percent. This allows companies to build solutions with this framework
for a much more realistic price tag. You are also laying a solid foundation
for your web application with features such as an API, a test environment,
seamless integration of web services and much more. This type of solution
caters to technical companies who have some internal resources to throw at the
project, a company that has the budget to hire a developer on a contract basis
or a company that will be integrating a lot of web services and needs a basis
for a mashup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously RoR has a lot going for it and it can be the perfect solution for a
large number of companies, but the truth of the matter is that you are still
building everything. The developers have to have solid foresight to build
everything in the ideal way for the company and must also be available when
you want to extend your application as your company grows or you want to chart
new territory on the web. This brings me to what I was actually sitting down
to write this article about; Drupal&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drupal is a freely available open source CMS that has recently started to
generate a bit of a buzz. Drupal is built on PHP with the intent of being
totally modular and is expected to be extended through pluggable modules.
Since I know I am going to be writing more about the inner workings of Drupal
over the next little while, I will approach this one from a higher level at
this point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CMS systems have gotten a bit of a bad wrap because many of them try to
implement everything you could ever want, but have problems giving you control
over it through an understandable interface. Drupal is a bit different because
it&amp;rsquo;s base install is relatively minimal and you then add what you need from a
long list of official or community made modules. You are able to get a working
version of your site up in a few minutes with user access control, the ability
to create and manage content as well as many other features such as a blog,
forum and internal messaging. You can completely customize the look and feel
of the site using templates that are easy to create or can be downloaded for
free from the drupal.org site. Because Drupal is free and open source there is
a large community of people who actively contribute modules, themes, ideas and
feedback if you are having problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So is a Drupal solution right for you? It is very possible that it could be.
With the startup cost being the price of a domain, hosting and a couple days
with a consultant you could be on your way to a successful online venture.
Drupal allows you to update and maintain your entire site your self without
having to work with a developer every time you want to make a change. This
allows you more flexibility at the start of the project and does not force you
to make expensive decisions now when you don&amp;rsquo;t have all the information you
need. Drupal allows your web presence to evolve as your company does without
forcing you to sink money into it, which is the case with many custom built
applications. Drupal is ideal for companies who know they need an online
presence but may not fully understand what to expect from an online venture.
It is also very good if you have content that is contributed by many people or
if you have content that changes on a regular basis. Drupal is great for
startups because of its low cost overhead and flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When making a decision like this you will need to do a lot of research. You
may want to contact consultants for a few different options and play them
against each other to get a feel for what they all have to offer and how their
solution will align with your business. If you are going to hire a consultant
or contract out development work, make sure that you are working with someone
who understands your business and future goals. Remember that this person is
going to be implementing your vision, so if they can&amp;rsquo;t see things the same way
as you then you are guaranteed to be disappointed with their result. Take your
time in the planning process and don&amp;rsquo;t force it. There is an ideal solution to
your problems, you just need to find the right people to help you realize it.
A bad solution is only slightly better than no solution.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>