<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Parallels on SwillOps</title>
    <link>http://willstevens.net/tags/parallels/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Parallels on SwillOps</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://willstevens.net/tags/parallels/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualized Development Environment</title>
      <link>http://willstevens.net/blog/virtualized-development-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://willstevens.net/blog/virtualized-development-environment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, while developing, I have had people looking over my shoulder and
asking questions like; &amp;ldquo;How are you able to code and test so quickly?&amp;rdquo; and
&amp;ldquo;You just wrote that, how is the person you are talking to on Skype able to
view and test it already?&amp;ldquo;. When I explain to them how my development
environment is set up, they usually replay, &amp;ldquo;you should really blog about
that&amp;rdquo;. So here it is&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, here is a little bit of background. I have been developing web
applications for quite a few years now and I always ran into the same issues;
browser compatibility, showing clients a work in progress, managing
development and production environments. A couple years ago I started working
for a new &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.syntenic.com/&#34;&gt;company&lt;/a&gt; and they asked me to brush up on
my knowledge of virtualization techniques. While researching what was
available in this space, my virtualized development environment was born.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a list of tools I use:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://store.apple.com/us/browse/home/shop_mac/family/macbook_pro&#34;&gt;A Mac Laptop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.parallels.com/products/virtuozzo/&#34;&gt;Parallels Virtuozzo Containers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.parallels.com/products/desktop/&#34;&gt;Parallels Desktop 4.0 for Mac&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://macromates.com/&#34;&gt;Textmate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://cyberduck.ch/&#34;&gt;Cyberduck&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://tredosoft.com/Multiple_IE&#34;&gt;Multiple IEs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For pretty much every site, I have a production (prod) environment and a
development (dev) environment. I want my dev environment to be an exact copy
of my prod environment so that when I make changes to it I know exactly how
the prod system is going to deal with the changes. Managing this was a PITA
until I found Parallels Virtuozzo Containers. I was then able to have one
machine that had both a prod and dev environment on it in different virtual
containers. There are quite a few cool features in Virtuozzo, but the main one
that is relevant to this post is the &amp;lsquo;Clone&amp;rsquo; feature. If you have a prod
machine up and running and you want to make changes, but you don&amp;rsquo;t want to
mess with the live machine, you can clone it to a new container and then
develop on that new dev container. This means that if I want to test some
changes to the site, I can just take 30 seconds to clone the live site, do the
changes and test&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am very comfortable with ssh and working in a terminal, but if you are
developing a lot, you do not want to have to deal with working only in VI or
VIM. Because of this, I use Cyberduck over SFTP to edit my code. Cyberduck is
an open source FTP client that is relatively simple and lightweight, but has
enough features that you will never feel handcuffed. I set my preferred editor
in Cyberduck to Textmate and my development environment is set up on my Mac. I
never have to copy files from the server to my machine and back because I just
edit them directly on my cloned dev machine. It really is as easy as clone,
edit, test&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest annoyances in web development is having to deal with cross
browser compatibility for your web apps. Developing for Internet Explorer is a
nightmare and because of this some developers neglect it. Unfortunately I do
not have that luxury and have to make sure that my sites work in all browsers.
Since I am working on a Mac, testing IE for Windows poses a small problem. I
use Parallels Desktop for Mac to solve that problem. Parallels Desktop is a
virtualization platform that allows you to install Windows on your Mac in a
way that allows you to run Windows programs without having to reboot your
machine. Basically, you just load the Windows machine and you have access to
all of your Mac and Windows applications at the same time. Since Windows does
not allow you to install both IE6 and IE7 on the same machine, I use Multiple
IEs as a little hack so that I can have both IE6 and IE7 on my Windows install
for testing purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is basically it&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pros:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Very fast to get development environments set up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your code is not on your laptop, so if it gets stolen, you are still fine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can make changes to code with the client on the phone so they can view the changes in real time (your dev machine is public).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your code is not actually in a code repository (I am working on setting up a version of this that is backed by Git).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you do not have a network connection, you can not work on the site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Ubuntu in Parallel to Mac OSX</title>
      <link>http://willstevens.net/blog/install-ubuntu-parallel-mac-osx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://willstevens.net/blog/install-ubuntu-parallel-mac-osx/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;If you are trying to do this you will need &lt;a href=&#34;http://kb.parallels.com/entry/32/568/&#34;&gt;Parallels Desktop 3.0 for Mac
(~$79.99 USD)&lt;/a&gt;. This software allows
you to run Windows and Linux on your Mac so you have access to all three
operating systems without rebooting. I think this will be an ideal web
developing environment, but that is another article all together&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Install Parallels Desktop 3.0 for Mac and then launch it. Go to &lt;strong&gt;File -&amp;gt;
New&lt;/strong&gt;. In the new window select &lt;strong&gt;Typical&lt;/strong&gt;, then click &lt;strong&gt;(Next)&lt;/strong&gt;. Select
&lt;strong&gt;Linux&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Ubuntu Linux&lt;/strong&gt;, then click &lt;strong&gt;(Next)&lt;/strong&gt;. Finish the guide with
the appropriate information that you want for the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got an error when I tried to install Ubuntu 7.10 (Gutsy):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The display server has been shut down about 6 times in the last 90 seconds.
It is likely that something bad is going on. Waiting for 2 minutes before
trying again on display.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you get this error, follow &lt;a href=&#34;http://kb.parallels.com/entry/32/568/&#34;&gt;this
guide&lt;/a&gt; in the very good knowledge base
provided by Parallels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;troubleshooting-section:ed60267dc24e98ddc27c68ab970f1367&#34;&gt;Troubleshooting Section:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;you-can-t-update-ubuntu:ed60267dc24e98ddc27c68ab970f1367&#34;&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t Update Ubuntu&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have to manually connect to your internet connection. Just go up to the
top right of your Ubuntu screen and select &amp;lsquo;Wired Network&amp;rsquo; from the network
monitor and it will connect (assuming your Mac has an internet connection).
Also since the install could not find a connection, it may have commented out
all of your repositories in &lt;code&gt;/etc/apt/sources.list&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;http://
ubuntuguide.org/wiki/Ubuntu:Gutsy#Manual_Method_for_Adding_Repositories&#34;&gt;Follow this guide&lt;/a&gt; to
set up your repositories (you should probably use these repositories anyway).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;can-t-start-ubuntu-after-an-update:ed60267dc24e98ddc27c68ab970f1367&#34;&gt;Can&amp;rsquo;t start Ubuntu after an Update&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some reason &lt;strong&gt;single&lt;/strong&gt; gets added back into the string &lt;code&gt;kernel /boot/....&lt;/code&gt;
in your &lt;code&gt;/boot/grub/menu.lst&lt;/code&gt; file. Refer back to &lt;a href=&#34;http://kb.parallels.com/entry/32/568/&#34;&gt;step 5 in this
guide&lt;/a&gt; to fix that problem.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; My machine crashed after the update and before the reboot which may
have caused this issue.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;cant-use-full-screen-resolution:ed60267dc24e98ddc27c68ab970f1367&#34;&gt;Cant use Full Screen Resolution&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are getting warnings telling you that you cant set a resolution that
size when you start the Ubuntu machine, &lt;a href=&#34;http://muffinresearch.co.uk/archives/2006/08/13/running-ubuntu-under-
parallels-desktop-for-mac/&#34;&gt;check out this
article&lt;/a&gt;. Basically, changing the setting in
&lt;code&gt;/etc/X11/xorg.conf&lt;/code&gt; does not work, you have to use &lt;code&gt;sudo dpkg-reconfigure 
-phigh xserver-xorg&lt;/code&gt; to change the resolution settings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point you should be set. Enjoy the wonderfulness of Linux on your
Mac&amp;hellip; :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>