<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Philanthropy on SwillOps</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/swillops.com/tags/philanthropy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Philanthropy on SwillOps</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/swillops.com/tags/philanthropy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Enabling Communities: What are we learning???</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/swillops.com/blog/enabling-communities-what-are-we-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/swillops.com/blog/enabling-communities-what-are-we-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently attended the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meshconference.com/&#34;&gt;Mesh 2007 Conference&lt;/a&gt;
in Toronto with many notable keynotes and guests. One of the more interesting
presentations I attended was &amp;lsquo;The Web and Philanthropy&amp;rsquo;. It was a conversation
led by Rob Hyndman with Tom Williams and Austin Hill, two people who are doing
a lot to facilitate philanthropy online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tom Williams is the founder of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.givemeaning.com/&#34;&gt;GiveMeaning&lt;/a&gt;, an
online application that allows people to search for and support an almost
endless number of worthwhile causes world wide. One of the (many) things that
sets GiveMeaning apart is that they do not take a cut from the donations given
through the site, so 100% of your contribution will be used for your specified
cause. They have set up an environment (really a community) that highlights
causes around the world and facilitates contributing to those causes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Austin Hill is one of the founders of ZeroKnowledge, now
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.radialpoint.com/&#34;&gt;RadialPoint&lt;/a&gt;, a company that focuses on privacy
issues online. He has recently been working on a number of projects to make a
worldwide difference online. A few of his projects include;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.akoha.org/&#34;&gt;Akoha&lt;/a&gt;, for gift giving (this is not public yet, so
all information about it is speculation); &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gifter.org/&#34;&gt;Gifter&lt;/a&gt;,
for charitable donations (to some extent);
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zerofootprint.net/&#34;&gt;Zerofootprint&lt;/a&gt;, a project to help reduce our
environmental footprint. These are only a few of his projects, but it goes
without saying that he has an in depth understanding of the web and the
communities built on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the main topics that was discusses was the ability to enable and
empower a community of people to make a difference. Obviously, from the links
above, both of these men have dedicated a large amount of time and energy into
understanding and working with communities, with the vision of making a
difference on a global scale. The success of these projects is a testament to
their ability to understand the many dynamics of web based communities and the
mobilizing power of their approach. So how do they see their communities and
what do they do to create this effect?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In many communities, the creators and moderators feel that they own the
community. It is theirs and the people who join are participating in an
environment which they control. This is not the case with the community that
Tom has created at GiveMeaning. He does not consider himself the owner of the
community, but an acting participant who is working to enable a group of like
minded people. He is mainly trying to build an environment that facilitates
the communities ability to act while centralizing the members views and
values. He is setting up a way for people to realize a return on their
generosity through a social network and differentiate them by their
conscientious choices. He is trying to create a way for people to generate
credibility in the community and then empower them through the founding
technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a new approach to community building and I feel that the application
of this approach is very valuable. In a world where we are surrounded by so
much negative content and influences, I feel that their positive and
empowering perspective fosters the underlying values of most people and gives
them an outlet that is not only constructive but influential to the rest
population.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>