<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Media on SwillOps</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/swillops.com/tags/media/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Media on SwillOps</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/swillops.com/tags/media/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Media vs New Media</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/swillops.com/blog/old-media-vs-new-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/swillops.com/blog/old-media-vs-new-media/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With many new types of media available online, the newspaper industry has been
loosing traction and are being forced to downsize. Is this just an inevitable
chain of events due to the onset of the information age, or do newspapers
still hold a valuable market and just need to adjust their thinking? I think
that the newspaper industry has a solid product and will continue to have a
market, but I feel that their market is changing and they need to reevaluate
their approach to the editorial consumer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Web logs (blogs) have developed a massive reader base in the past few years.
They are easy to access and are often quicker than newspapers to publish
breaking news. Many blogs are directed at a specific field of knowledge, so if
you are interested in one of the articles you will most likely be interested
in others by the same author. Many authors have become very well known and
their work is checked on a regular basis or referenced with regard to their
topic of expertise. Authors build a reputation and credibility through the
quality of their work, but do not have an obligation to produce content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Newspaper columnists, on the other hand, are paid by newspaper companies and
must create content in order to keep their jobs. The newspaper industry is
therefor paying for consistent and quality journalism through infrastructure
and must keep up sales if it is going to stay in business. The one major thing
that I feel is lacking in the newspapers approach and presentation is the
human aspect. They have tried to centralize their view to be &amp;ldquo;the paper&amp;rsquo;s&amp;rdquo;
view and with that have not been presenting their contributors well enough. It
is difficult to know exactly who wrote the article you are reading in a paper
because you only have a name and picture to go on. Unless you follow a
specific writer&amp;rsquo;s work, you have no frame of reference to fully understand
their stance. This is an area where I feel the blogisphere excels. Because the
majority of the writing done in blogs are opinion pieces, writers must build
credibility as a person in order for anyone to take them seriously. Newspapers
already have the initial credibility, so why haven&amp;rsquo;t they tried to create
personal credibility for their writers and create aggregated environments of
their work? A lot of this comes down to the way the newspaper industry has
tried to adapt to blogs entering the market. They have taken a head on
approach, mainly because they have an arrogance about the quality of their
content and feel that they should not have to compete on the same level. If
you really think about this, it is an amazing situation for the newspapers
because the majority of blogs are flooding a large amount of lower quality
content into the public domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what do newspaper companies have to gain and loose from presenting their
writers online and giving them an online credibility? They would tell you that
they would loose potential sales because they are releasing the same content
free online, so why would anyone pay for it? The truth of the matter is that
newspapers have a huge tactile advantage to blogs. Once you know which writers
you like and who they write for, you are more likely to buy the paper to read
in a coffee shop. Unlike a laptop, if you get get ketchup on a paper you
probably won&amp;rsquo;t go insane. People already spend more time than they would like
in front of their computer, so they will take advantage of the chance to catch
up on their favorite reading without going bug eyed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Newspaper companies are already having to lay off employees because of reduced
sales. I feel that the jobs being lost are a direct result of their inability
to adapt to the information age and by not taking the initiative to compete in
the new technology market. They are set in their ways and are not paying
attention to the current trends in the population. There is not a future in
cutting down large areas of trees to feed paper mills which pollute our
environment so that a newspaper can to placed on every person&amp;rsquo;s doorstep every
morning. A large percentage of these papers are never even read and are just
tossed in the recycling bin (if not worse, the trash). The newspaper industry
needs to become an on demand service with improved social interests if it
expects to be able to compete in the upcoming era&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>