<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Development on SwillOps</title>
    <link>http://swill.github.io/swillops.com/tags/development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Development on SwillOps</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://swill.github.io/swillops.com/tags/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtualized Development Environment</title>
      <link>http://swill.github.io/swillops.com/blog/virtualized-development-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://swill.github.io/swillops.com/blog/virtualized-development-environment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, while developing, I have had people looking over my shoulder and
asking questions like; &amp;ldquo;How are you able to code and test so quickly?&amp;rdquo; and
&amp;ldquo;You just wrote that, how is the person you are talking to on Skype able to
view and test it already?&amp;ldquo;. When I explain to them how my development
environment is set up, they usually replay, &amp;ldquo;you should really blog about
that&amp;rdquo;. So here it is&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, here is a little bit of background. I have been developing web
applications for quite a few years now and I always ran into the same issues;
browser compatibility, showing clients a work in progress, managing
development and production environments. A couple years ago I started working
for a new &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.syntenic.com/&#34;&gt;company&lt;/a&gt; and they asked me to brush up on
my knowledge of virtualization techniques. While researching what was
available in this space, my virtualized development environment was born.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a list of tools I use:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://store.apple.com/us/browse/home/shop_mac/family/macbook_pro&#34;&gt;A Mac Laptop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.parallels.com/products/virtuozzo/&#34;&gt;Parallels Virtuozzo Containers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.parallels.com/products/desktop/&#34;&gt;Parallels Desktop 4.0 for Mac&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://macromates.com/&#34;&gt;Textmate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://cyberduck.ch/&#34;&gt;Cyberduck&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://tredosoft.com/Multiple_IE&#34;&gt;Multiple IEs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For pretty much every site, I have a production (prod) environment and a
development (dev) environment. I want my dev environment to be an exact copy
of my prod environment so that when I make changes to it I know exactly how
the prod system is going to deal with the changes. Managing this was a PITA
until I found Parallels Virtuozzo Containers. I was then able to have one
machine that had both a prod and dev environment on it in different virtual
containers. There are quite a few cool features in Virtuozzo, but the main one
that is relevant to this post is the &amp;lsquo;Clone&amp;rsquo; feature. If you have a prod
machine up and running and you want to make changes, but you don&amp;rsquo;t want to
mess with the live machine, you can clone it to a new container and then
develop on that new dev container. This means that if I want to test some
changes to the site, I can just take 30 seconds to clone the live site, do the
changes and test&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am very comfortable with ssh and working in a terminal, but if you are
developing a lot, you do not want to have to deal with working only in VI or
VIM. Because of this, I use Cyberduck over SFTP to edit my code. Cyberduck is
an open source FTP client that is relatively simple and lightweight, but has
enough features that you will never feel handcuffed. I set my preferred editor
in Cyberduck to Textmate and my development environment is set up on my Mac. I
never have to copy files from the server to my machine and back because I just
edit them directly on my cloned dev machine. It really is as easy as clone,
edit, test&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest annoyances in web development is having to deal with cross
browser compatibility for your web apps. Developing for Internet Explorer is a
nightmare and because of this some developers neglect it. Unfortunately I do
not have that luxury and have to make sure that my sites work in all browsers.
Since I am working on a Mac, testing IE for Windows poses a small problem. I
use Parallels Desktop for Mac to solve that problem. Parallels Desktop is a
virtualization platform that allows you to install Windows on your Mac in a
way that allows you to run Windows programs without having to reboot your
machine. Basically, you just load the Windows machine and you have access to
all of your Mac and Windows applications at the same time. Since Windows does
not allow you to install both IE6 and IE7 on the same machine, I use Multiple
IEs as a little hack so that I can have both IE6 and IE7 on my Windows install
for testing purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is basically it&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pros:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Very fast to get development environments set up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your code is not on your laptop, so if it gets stolen, you are still fine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can make changes to code with the client on the phone so they can view the changes in real time (your dev machine is public).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your code is not actually in a code repository (I am working on setting up a version of this that is backed by Git).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you do not have a network connection, you can not work on the site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From the beginning...</title>
      <link>http://swill.github.io/swillops.com/blog/beginning/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://swill.github.io/swillops.com/blog/beginning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I started working with web based development and design when I was 16. I
started out working mainly with graphic design and then moving more towards
web development as I got closer to heading off to university.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2005 I got my bachelors degree from McGill University in Computer Science.
I had done quite a bit of freelance work with the web while I was in school,
but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really considering it as a career at the time. I thought it would
be smart to become a &amp;ldquo;developer&amp;rdquo; rather than a &amp;ldquo;web developer&amp;rdquo;, so when I
graduated I started working for a pretty big company coding in C# on .NET. It
didn&amp;rsquo;t take me long to realize that I don&amp;rsquo;t think the way that &amp;lsquo;versioned&amp;rsquo;
software developers think. Added to that, this was my first experience working
with a big company. I had no control over our shipped product, I was just a
cog in a big (inefficient) machine. I realized that I had not become a
&amp;ldquo;developer&amp;rdquo; at all, but a &amp;ldquo;programmer&amp;rdquo;. You may be thinking that there is no
difference between the two, so let me clarify my point. I was once told, &amp;ldquo;a
software developer is like a poet or a painter. They all start with a blank
piece of paper and their only limit is their imagination&amp;rdquo;. I find this very
true. As a software developer you are dealing directly with a client and you
are working together with them to solve their problems in the best way
possible. By intimately understanding the clients needs you have more freedom
to be creative and build an elegant solution. On the flip side, as a
programmer you have very little freedom. You are given a strict set of
specifications that need to be implemented and your job is to build it. The
problem is, most of the time this set of specifications has gone through about
6 levels of documentation, from a high level estimate all the way down to the
technical spec document that you were handed. The client is often only
consulted for the first half of that documentation process, so it is very
possible that right from the beginning you are not even building what the
client needs. Of course, when the client is not happy with the end result, the
programmer takes all the flak. Being a very entrepreneurial person, this
setting really was not working out for me. I began looking into the web
environment again because I had always enjoyed working in that field. In my
research to get caught up with all the new happenings in this industry I
realized that my year and a half away from web development had put me way
behind. I knew right away that I was in the wrong industry and started taking
steps to correct my previous decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update: I have quit my job and started working for a small company as a web
developer and it has been amazing. I work too much now days, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t be
happier&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>